This indicator is one of the simplest
things that I've ever used in my entire
life. Not only did it make me $11,000
last week, but it made me over $10,000
this week and as you can see, a 100%
green month. So, in this video, I'm
going to break down the entire custom
strategy for you from start to finish.
And just to show you how simple this
indicator is, I am going to put on a
15minute timer and explain the entire
thing to you in under 15 minutes. So,
let's get started. The first thing that
we need to do is go over to our
indicators tab and type in volume
weighted average price. You're going to
see right here this indicator pops up. I
don't use any of the other ones. I use
volume weighted average price and that
is it. And this is the only indicator
that you need on your chart. Literally
like you can remove everything else.
This is the only one that actually
matters in my opinion. Now what we're
going to do is we're going to change the
way that this looks a little bit. First
off, before we do that, I want to tell
you we're going to go over literally how
to set the entire indicator up, the
whole custom trading strategy. And then
I'm going to show you at the very end of
this video the biggest mistakes that
people make while trading VWAP. And I'm
going to try to do this all in under 15
minutes for you. Slow the video down,
pause it if you have to. I want this to
be a good video for you and just break
down everything. So here's the custom
setup. We're going to double click here
and go to the settings. We're going to
turn off upper band one, lower band one,
and bandsville one. Right? I just want
this blue line on my chart because
everything else to me personally doesn't
matter. I'm going to trade this blue
line only and this is the only thing
that I actually care about. Now, here's
how VWAP actually works, guys. What
you're going to notice on VWAP is that
it follows trend very closely, right?
So, if trend is moving like this, you're
going to see VWAP moving along with it.
Now, since this is a it's essentially
like a moving average where it moves
with the price, but it also includes
volume as well. So one thing that you
will see is if price is moving like this
but then starts to consolidate VWAP will
move up sharply and then have a giant
flat line at the end here. So for my
trading the the number one thing that I
want to do is I don't want to trade
while price of is flat. All right. I
don't want to trade when VWAP is flat.
So what we're looking for here is
something like this. If VWOP stays
anything like this I'm avoiding pretty
much the entire day. And so this is how
I avoid some of my biggest losing days
and some of you see online people losing
thousands and thousands of dollars
trading. If you just throw this
indicator on your chart, you would
exactly know when to skip, right? You'd
know when to skip and you know exactly
when to take trades. And so using this
indicator, the only thing I want to do
is take sharp moves because those sharp
moves are going to have the most
momentum behind them. Now, this is live,
so I'm going to be drinking water
and hopefully that doesn't slow down my
explanation. But, so we know exactly
what VWAP is, right? The next thing we
have to understand is how to actually
use the indicator. And so, for me, I am
a trendbased trader. I want to make sure
that no matter what I'm doing, I'm
trading inside of the trend because, as
you know, the trend is your friend.
That's what everybody says. So, what
we're going to do is we're going to go
to the higher time frame, something like
the 1 hour, the 4 hour. You could
consider the 15minute, but typically if
I'm going to be finding trend, I'm going
to the one hour. And I want to make sure
that I am trading along with the trend.
So, for example, here we know that we
have an uptrend. And the only way for us
to have a downtrend is if we break this
area right here. Because if we break
this low, then we end up flipping to the
downside. So, in this scenario, when I
want to take a trade to the downside, I
have to have that change of character.
Now, what I'm going to do is show you
guys exactly what happens when you drop
to the fiveinut time frame. This is the
trading the the time frame that I use
most on this trading strategy is going
to be the five minute. We have that low
there that we need to see get broken,
right? For us to actually have trend in
our favor. So, this is the first example
I'm going to show you of this trading
strategy. What we need to see is a
breakthrough VWAP, right? And let me
start a new replay. I know you guys hate
replay, but I want to show you exactly
how the strategy works. If you want to
see a live trade, comment the word live
trade or comment just let me know that
you want to see live trades down below
and I will show you live trades. But
here's the deal. I can't really explain
the strategy perfectly for you guys live
because I'm trading, right? So, let's go
over this right now. Okay, so the first
thing we need to see is going to be a
break of VWAP to the downside, right? We
know that we want downside because like
I showed you earlier, we have that
change of character. So when we get that
change of character there, we need to
see a retest of VWOP. Okay? So this next
candle that comes out, the next thing we
need to see is a retest of VWAP. So here
in this situation, we get that retest of
VWAP. The next thing I'd want to see,
and this is a part of my TFC entry model
that I talk about all of the time, is
going to be a continuation. Right? I am
a continuationbased trader. I trade
based off of the momentum of the market.
That's why you see me having massive
moves all the time on social media
because excuse me, I want to make sure
that I capitalize on the biggest moves
that are happening at the time. And so
the biggest way to do that is by
catching the trend, right? So this
continuation is going to be when we
continue down here to break lows. So, if
we see a low break, I'm interested in
shorts in this scenario. Now, I'm going
to show you another scenario if time
permits. I'm looking at the time right
now. We have nine minutes and 50 seconds
left. So, I'm going to go over as many
scenarios as I possibly can and break
this strategy just as full in-depth as I
can in 15. So, we have that break of
that low right there. Right? That's what
we're looking for for us to get into
this position. Now, stop losses while
using this strategy are going to be over
VWAP pretty much always, right? I want
stop losses over VWOP and I want stop-
losses over the previous candle high if
I can get that. So, if we take a look at
higher time frame, right, let's see if
we have any good stop losses for us.
So, there's [clears throat] two
potential uh targets, not stop losses.
There's two potential targets that I'm
looking for here, which is going to be
this area down here, which is just where
that overall resting liquidity is. And
of course, if you guys have watched my
videos before, you know that I use FIBS
quite often. So, we would use this as a,
you know, first target potentially and
use this as our final target. So, I'll
go ahead and throw this final target on
the chart and let's go back to the five
minute time frame. So, what we're
looking for is an entry below this low.
We'll see what happens on the next
candle. We don't get an entry here.
Beautiful. We're going to move it and we
just go to the next candle after that.
Right. Well, all I'm looking for is a
break of lows. I don't care which candle
gets broken. I want to see the break of
lows.
Now,
we're going to look to see which one
breaks. This low gets broken right here,
which means that we are going to most
likely get an entry right there to the
downside. On the break of that low, stop
losses, like I said, go above the
previous candle high. Targets come all
the way down here. This is a a 491 tick
position, which is really nice. So,
let's see what happens at this point. We
have that entry, and all we need to see
now is the failure to continue down.
Beautiful, right? We see the same thing
happening literally every single day in
the market. This is the entry model that
I use every single day. Trade with the
trend failure continuation. But here's
the deal. You're probably still using
this indicator wrong because a lot of
people don't realize that there's one
main thing that you can do on the exit
side that makes things so powerful using
it. So, when it comes to VWAP and when
it comes to using this, right, a lot of
people just exit right here at their at
their final target and they call it a
day. Well, there's something that you
can do since VWAP rides with the trend.
There's two things you can do. The first
is that you exit whenever price breaks
VWOP to the upside. So, for example, if
we let this trend just continue and
continue, we would exit here in this
area. But for me, for my exits, the way
that I like to do them is by adding a
second indicator and going to moving
average exponential. Right? We're going
to add this indicator right here. This
is the 9 EMA. And I throw this on my
chart as an entry point or as an exit
point. So that way you can see exactly
where to exit on this chart. And it's
typically going to be in this area right
here when we close above that 9 EMA. So
that's if you want to hold trades
longer. Now, let's find another scenario
right here so that way I can show you
exactly how VWAP works even further. Um,
we can just literally go right here. For
example, we have our trend, right? And
I'm just going to do the same thing over
and over for you guys. So that way you
see the actual potential of this
strategy. We see that we're pushing up
and we're coming back down to VWAP.
Right now, all we need to see is a push
up over highs. Okay? It's the same thing
every single time. We're going to look
for a push up over highs with a stop
loss below VWAP. And we're going to look
for targets to be up where there is an
area of liquidity. So that would be for
here would be this area right here.
Right? Just looking for the next big
area of liquidity up. And that happens
to be right there for this area. So on
this position here, we see a 1.6 to1
risk-to-reward, a profitable trade if we
can get it. And the next candle ends up
not seeing that break. So now we're
going to go based on the next candle in
the sequence and stop losses are going
to go below the previous candle low.
Right? This is what we're doing pretty
much every single time. We're going to
see if we can get that break of those
highs, which we do end up getting. And
we enter right there on the break. I
don't enter on the close of the candle
because for me, I want to make sure that
I get the best entry possible. Right? If
you entered on the close of the candle,
you would have entered all the way over
here if you had waited for a close of
the candle. Right for me, I'm getting
this entry and I'm catching so much more
on this move. And so, we just want to
let this trade run from there and see if
we can get ourselves a push all the way
up to targets. Now, first target for
this trade probably would have been up
here for me. Second target would have
been this area where we were at right
now. And as you can see, this trade ends
up being extremely profitable for us. we
get full target hit, which I didn't know
that that was going to happen, but we
get full target hit right there. Now,
that's a bearish or a bullish example
and we had a bearish example. Here's
some things that we have to pay
attention to and what to avoid when
we're trading this strategy. The first
is going to be if we don't get a break
of lows, right? A lot of people are
going to try to find this this like
rejection or reversal trade here. This
one right here where they're like,
"Okay, we can get this reversal and push
to the downside." If you do not see a
break of lows, there is no point of
trading this trade, right? If even if it
comes down and taps the lows and then
bounces off, right? Even if it comes
down to tap those lows, we are not going
to enter. We want to see a break of the
lows for us to get into anything. Now,
in this scenario, we still have bullish
trends. So, there's no reason to even do
that. But let's say that you were
trading here, right? Let's go with this
example right here. Here, we only have
four minutes left. So, I'm going to make
sure I break this down for you as
quickly as I possibly can. But here in
this scenario, if we had this entry that
we were looking for, which you know that
we are looking for a break, a retest of
that level and then a break of lows. If
we had just come down and stopped right
here and then flipped, we're not going
to enter there, right? We want to see a
smooth break of lows for us to get that
entry. And as you can see here, this
ends up being an extremely profitable
position. Now, I know what you're
thinking. do it live, right? Well, guys,
there's not that many opportunities. As
you can see, here's one area. Here's
another area. Both of them have trades
present. If we go the next day, there's
only one area with a trade present. So,
take a look. This sets you up for one
trade per day. And all of your trades
that you're taking are going to be
bangers, right? Even if that's the case,
even if you're getting a trade that's
multiple trades per day, we're not going
to be taking that because look, this is
a flat line in VWAP. We're going to be
avoiding that as much as we possibly
can. We want to trade inside of actual
like real conditions in the market, not
this garbage. So, let's take a look and
wait for a day that we actually get a
smooth move, which is going to be this
day right here. The easiest entry model
of all time. I'm telling you, this is
the TFC entry model. Trend, fail,
continue. Simplest thing that you can
ever do in your entire life. Take a look
how we come up over VWAP here. We retest
the VWAP and then we continue to the
upside. All we want to do is enter on
the break of this high. That's it. Put
your stop loss underneath VWAP and put
your target up to the next area of
liquidity, which I would assume is this
area right here. Um, I don't know how
much further this ends up going, but if
I were to find out, and I don't have
that much time to find out, but if I
were to find out, I would say that this
would go all the way up to probably
around this area here because this would
be our 50% on the fibs. So, let's play
it out. And as you can see, we end up
breaking that high right here. So, this
is where I would get my entry. And we
would let this trade fly for as long as
we possibly can. If you wanted to, like
I said before, you can have your 9 EMA
to help you ride the position to the
upside. So, take a look here. As you can
see, this would tell you to exit right
here. And now you have yourself a very,
very profitable strategy using only one
indicator. Two, if you wanted to include
the EMA as like an actual indicator that
you're using in your strategy. So,
really, really, really simple trading
strategy that I have been using for a
very long time. And honestly guys, it
can't get much more simple than this. So
what I want you to do is I want you to
go and actually practice this in the
market. Don't just take my word for it.
I really don't want you to take my word
for it. I want you to go and practice
the trade. Go and back test the trade.
Go and forward test the trade and tell
me what you think about it. Right? Don't
just tell me, ah, he's a replay trade or
a scam. I don't care. Right? What I want
you to do is test the thing yourself
because it's a good strategy and it's
made me a lot of money. So, I want you
to make money as well. Here's another
scenario where we see the same thing,
right? We see that break, we see that
retest, and then a fail and a
continuation through VWAP. So, this is a
little bit of a different example, a
little bit of a unique example, but we
end up getting a fire trade there to
continue to the downside and on this
position. So, if you guys enjoyed that,
uh, if you wanted more in-depth,
literally like more examples or live
trades, just comment down below and I'll
be able to do that for you guys using
just this TFC entry model, you can see
students like Evan absolutely crushing
it every single day and Kim making over
literally $12,000 in one day. So, I've
taught this model to over 500 people. It
has worked for a lot of students. And if
you're interested in working directly
with me one-on-one and having me looking
over your shoulder every single day,
literally helping you build this entire
strategy and actually helping you scale
to the point where you can get to where
some of these students are right here
that you are currently seeing, then go
ahead and go to the first link in the
description and apply to join Simply
Options Academy. These students here
aren't this successful just because
they're learning a strategy. It's
because they're learning everything else
that comes along with trading that makes
trading so difficult. So, what I want
you to do is there's going to be a video
popping up on the screen right now. It's
going to be somewhere right here in the
middle, and it's going to go over
psychology because that's going to be
the most important thing when it comes
to your trading. This strategy is great
and all, but I want you to get even
further. I want you to be even more
successful as a trader. So, do me a
favor, click that video and watch it
because if you're struggling right now,
it's because you don't have a strategy
that actually works or you don't have
the mentals to back a working strategy.
That being said, I'll see you guys all
later. Adios everybody. Goodbye.